<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Web on Mohamed Gaafar's Portfiolio</title><link>https://www.mngaafar.com/tags/web/</link><description>Recent content in Web on Mohamed Gaafar's Portfiolio</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 18:17:54 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mngaafar.com/tags/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Experience Building a Fast and User-Friendly Website with Hugo and Netlify CMS</title><link>https://www.mngaafar.com/projects/creations/my-experience-building-a-fast-and-user-friendly-website-with-hugo-and-netlify-cms/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 16:06:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mngaafar.com/projects/creations/my-experience-building-a-fast-and-user-friendly-website-with-hugo-and-netlify-cms/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Building the CUERT Website with Hugo and Netlify CMS&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As web development team leader for the Cairo University Eco-Racing Team (CUERT), I wanted to create a website that reflects our innovative spirit and showcases our dedication to sustainable transportation. I chose Hugo and Netlify CMS as the foundation for the project. Here&amp;rsquo;s why:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Speed and Performance:&lt;/strong> Hugo is renowned for its blazingly fast performance, making it ideal for building websites that deliver a great user experience.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Developer-Friendly:&lt;/strong> As a developer myself, I appreciate Hugo&amp;rsquo;s simplicity and flexibility. It gave me full control to customize the site&amp;rsquo;s structure, design, and functionality to our specific needs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Content Management Made Easy:&lt;/strong> Netlify CMS offers a streamlined way to manage and update website content without needing in-depth coding knowledge. This was important for us since non-technical team members also need to contribute to the website.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Project Walkthrough&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>