<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Upper Limb on Mohamed Gaafar's Portfiolio</title><link>https://www.mngaafar.com/tags/upper-limb/</link><description>Recent content in Upper Limb on Mohamed Gaafar's Portfiolio</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 11:44:31 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mngaafar.com/tags/upper-limb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Scoping Review - Immersive Virtual Reality Games in Neuromotor Rehabilitation with Brain-Computer Interfaces</title><link>https://www.mngaafar.com/publications/scoping-review/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mngaafar.com/publications/scoping-review/</guid><description>&lt;p>This review delves into the pioneering integration of immersive Virtual Reality (VR) and Brain-Computer Interface (BCI) technologies in neuromotor rehabilitation. Highlighting a significant leap in the realm of therapeutic interventions, the paper, titled &amp;ldquo;Immersive Virtual Reality Games in Neuromotor Rehabilitation with Brain-Computer Interfaces: A Scoping Review,&amp;rdquo; encapsulates an extensive synthesis of current research, offering a comprehensive understanding of the field&amp;rsquo;s trajectory and potential.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Key takeaways include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Demographic Diversity and Wide Age Range&lt;/strong>: The studies encompass a broad demographic, underscoring VR and BCI&amp;rsquo;s potential across various age groups and health conditions, particularly emphasizing the inclusion of stroke and cerebral palsy patients.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Technological Evolution&lt;/strong>: A shift from traditional CAVE systems to the Oculus Rift marks a significant technological advancement, reflecting user preference and accessibility.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Motor Imagery (MI) Paradigm&lt;/strong>: The unanimous adoption of MI across studies accentuates its critical role in enhancing neuroplasticity and improving rehabilitation outcomes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Design and Engagement&lt;/strong>: The diverse game design elements, focusing on scoring, embodiment, and customization, demonstrate the versatility of immersive BCI-VR games in addressing motor impairments and engaging users.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Future Directions&lt;/strong>: While revealing promising results, the review also identifies areas needing attention, such as the limited focus on gamification and the predominance of healthy participants, suggesting a pathway for more inclusive and engaging future research.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>