<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Mohamed Gaafar's Portfiolio</title><link>https://www.mngaafar.com/projects/creations/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Mohamed Gaafar's Portfiolio</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 09:28:51 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mngaafar.com/projects/creations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>TMS Motor Mapping Visualization - GSoC 24 @Invesalius</title><link>https://www.mngaafar.com/projects/creations/tms-motor-mapping-visualization-gsoc-24-invesalius/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 05:48:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mngaafar.com/projects/creations/tms-motor-mapping-visualization-gsoc-24-invesalius/</guid><description>&lt;p>This project introduces a new Motor Mapping Visualization feature to Invesalius, offering enhanced capabilities for visualizing and interacting with Motor Evoked Potential (MEP) data&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="features">Features:&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Heatmap visualization on brain surface based on Motor evoked potentials&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Interactive MEP value adjustment and session persistence&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 Customizable colormap ranges&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Brain surface selection&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Modifiable gaussian parameters for surface and points interpolation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>10 Different colormaps to choose from&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="quick-runthrough">Quick Runthrough&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The following animation demonstrates the interactive workflow, allowing for real-time exploration of MEP data and visualization customization.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Advancing Neurorehabilitation: Integrating Brain Computer Interfaces in Virtual Reality for Motor Rehabilitation of Stroke Patients</title><link>https://www.mngaafar.com/projects/creations/advancing-neurorehabilitation-integrating-brain-computer-interfaces-in-virtual-reality-for-motor-rehabilitation-of-stroke-patients/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 17:55:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mngaafar.com/projects/creations/advancing-neurorehabilitation-integrating-brain-computer-interfaces-in-virtual-reality-for-motor-rehabilitation-of-stroke-patients/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the quest to enhance neurorehabilitation, our team at Cairo University, is pioneering a project that integrates the immersive world of Virtual Reality (VR) with the groundbreaking potential of Brain-Computer Interface (BCI) systems. This initiative is not just a testament to technological innovation but also a beacon of hope for individuals suffering from the debilitating effects of stroke and brain injuries. We invite esteemed colleagues and professors to explore the nuances and progress of our endeavor as we apply for further study and research opportunities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Empowering the Visually Impaired: A Leap Forward with Vision Transformers</title><link>https://www.mngaafar.com/projects/creations/empowering-the-visually-impaired-a-leap-forward-with-vision-transformers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 06:17:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mngaafar.com/projects/creations/empowering-the-visually-impaired-a-leap-forward-with-vision-transformers/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the pursuit of creating a more inclusive world, our team has embarked on a groundbreaking project: the &amp;ldquo;Blind Assistance Image Recognition System.&amp;rdquo; This initiative represents a significant leap forward in assistive technology, aiming to transform the lives of visually impaired individuals by enabling them to understand and interact with their environment more effectively.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Revolutionizing Perception with ViT-GPT2 Integration&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our system harnesses the power of the Vision Transformer (ViT) and GPT-2, revolutionizing image interpretation. ViT dissects images into patches, analyzing them for a contextual understanding, while the encoder-decoder architecture of GPT-2 takes these insights and translates them into detailed descriptions. This synergy allows for a nuanced perception of the environment, moving beyond mere object identification to a comprehensive narrative of the scene, significantly enhancing the experience for visually impaired individuals. This integrated approach offers a more profound and contextual understanding than traditional methods, paving the way for a new era in assistive technology.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Experience Building a Fast and User-Friendly Website with Hugo and Netlify CMS</title><link>https://www.mngaafar.com/projects/creations/my-experience-building-a-fast-and-user-friendly-website-with-hugo-and-netlify-cms/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 16:06:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.mngaafar.com/projects/creations/my-experience-building-a-fast-and-user-friendly-website-with-hugo-and-netlify-cms/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Building the CUERT Website with Hugo and Netlify CMS&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As web development team leader for the Cairo University Eco-Racing Team (CUERT), I wanted to create a website that reflects our innovative spirit and showcases our dedication to sustainable transportation. I chose Hugo and Netlify CMS as the foundation for the project. Here&amp;rsquo;s why:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Speed and Performance:&lt;/strong> Hugo is renowned for its blazingly fast performance, making it ideal for building websites that deliver a great user experience.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Developer-Friendly:&lt;/strong> As a developer myself, I appreciate Hugo&amp;rsquo;s simplicity and flexibility. It gave me full control to customize the site&amp;rsquo;s structure, design, and functionality to our specific needs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Content Management Made Easy:&lt;/strong> Netlify CMS offers a streamlined way to manage and update website content without needing in-depth coding knowledge. This was important for us since non-technical team members also need to contribute to the website.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Project Walkthrough&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>